{
    "id": "779979a05f3848adac0c3825b3fc75f0",
    "title": "Present Or Future Tense Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "a8e2294d79e548ea8eda419200be5058",
            "title": "Present Or Future Tense",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Granny’s plane ……………………….. at three o’clock.",
                    "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about events which are part of a timetable.",
                    "answers": [
                        "arrive",
                        "arrives",
                        "will arrive"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The next semester …………………………. on November 10th.",
                    "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about events which are part of a timetable.",
                    "answers": [
                        "begin",
                        "begins",
                        "will begin"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will pay you back when I ………………… a job.",
                    "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "get",
                        "got",
                        "will get"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will call you when dinner ………………………… ready.",
                    "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "was",
                        "will be"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Rani ………………………….. for a drink.",
                    "description": "The present continuous is often used to talk about future events when the arrangement already exists.",
                    "answers": [
                        "comes",
                        "will come",
                        "is coming"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘The phone is ringing.’ ‘I …………………… it.’",
                    "description": "We use the simple future to announce decisions taken at the moment of speaking.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will answer",
                        "answer",
                        "am answering"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………………….. the tickets but you have to buy the dinner.",
                    "description": "We use the simple future tense to talk about our decisions and intentions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "will buy",
                        "would buy",
                        "should buy"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I think I ……………………….. it.",
                    "description": "We do not use the simple present or present continuous to announce decisions that are made at the moment of speaking.",
                    "answers": [
                        "buy",
                        "am buying",
                        "will buy"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………………… I open a window?",
                    "description": "We use shall in questions asking for instructions and decisions.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Shall",
                        "Will",
                        "Would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Let’s go and see her, …………………………. we?",
                    "description": "We use shall in question tags after let.",
                    "answers": [
                        "should",
                        "shall",
                        "would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………… you get me some apples when you’re out?",
                    "description": "We use will to ask people to do things.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Shall",
                        "Should",
                        "Will"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Get me a cup of coffee, ………………………… you?",
                    "description": "We use will in instructions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "shall",
                        "should",
                        "will"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}